well this year is Canada's 150th and our
friends at the Calgary Zoo are
celebrating Canadian animals we're here
at the zoo today to find out more about
our country's most amazing and iconic
native species with the bottomless
appetite and a love for all things
edible the grizzly bear has warmed our
hearts right on to our list of Canada's
most amazing and unique native species
the largest terrestrial animal in North
America the large M lumber and wood
bison were once widespread and abundant
across northern Canada
when someone mentions the call of the
wild
chances are you imagine the haunting
howl of the gray wolf these intelligent
social canines are known for their
strong family bonds it is both dangerous
and beautiful the Cougar is a reclusive
and often misunderstood predator with no
fear of heights and a seeming ability to
defy gravity the rocky mountain goat
makes its home where few others are
sure-footed enough to tread some call
this boreal ghost the phantom of the
north for its ability to blend into the
forest the beautiful grey owl is the
largest owl on earth it wasn't that long
ago that there were less than two dozen
of this majestic flyer left in the world
the whooping crane is slowly making its
way back from the brink of extinction
many people have never heard of let
alone seen the largest member of the
squirrel family the lovable Vancouver
Island Marmot is currently said to be
the most critically endangered animal in
Canada these tiny owls rely on their
prairie neighbors to provide their
subterranean residences giving them the
name burrowing owl this adorable owl is
now a protected species due to habitat
loss across the prairies no other animal
changes and transforms their environment
more than the industrious beer and for
nearly 250 years the fur trade was a
vast commercial enterprise across the
wild forested expanse of what is now
Canada forever linking the beaver with
the history of our beloved country well
the next time you visit the Calgary Zoo
remember you're not only getting the
opportunity to see some amazing animals
but you're also helping to contribute to
the ongoing conservation research of
Canadian endangered wildlife